<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Community | Jason Leveille]]></title>
  <link href="http://jasonleveille.com/blog/categories/community/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jasonleveille.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-03T16:29:02-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://jasonleveille.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jason Leveille]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[i@leve.us]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Civic Hacking with #HFCWesternMA, #hackforchange]]></title>
    <link href="http://jasonleveille.com/blog/2013/06/civic-hacking-with-hfcwesternma-hackforchange/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-03T10:07:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://jasonleveille.com/blog/2013/06/civic-hacking-with-hfcwesternma-hackforchange</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/molly_ampersand/8914863543/" title="Hanging the National Day of Civic Hacking banner by Molly Ampersand, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3686/8914863543_eff66535e4_c.jpg" style="width: 100%" alt="Hanging the National Day of Civic Hacking banner"></a></p>

<p>This past weekend ~100 hackers from all over Massachussetts (and Eliot, ME :) generously donated their time and expertise for the <a href="http://hackforchange.org/">National Day of Civic Hacking</a> event for <a href="http://hackforwesternmass.org/">Western Mass</a>.  This inspiring event was one of 95 held across the country.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>The event will bring together citizens, software developers, and entrepreneurs from all over the nation to collaboratively create, build, and invent new solutions using publicly-released data, code and technology to solve challenges relevant to our neighborhoods, our cities, our states and our country.</p><footer><strong>@hackforchange <a href="http://hackforchange.org/page/about">http://hackforchange.org/page/about</a> About National Day of Civic Hacking</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<!--more-->


<h2>The Projects</h2>

<p>There were some <a href="http://hackforwesternmass.org/challenges">outstanding projects</a> at the event.  Turnout was great (~100 hackers), so each project seemed to be adequately represented.  A strong indicator of success were the presentations on Sunday.  The quality of the <a href="https://github.com/hackforwesternmass">work produced</a> was impressive.  I&rsquo;ve continued to see activity on GitHub since Sunday afternoon.  It&rsquo;s clear that the folks involved with each project care about its success, and that they&rsquo;re willing to see it through to completion.</p>

<h3>Visualizing Federal Data</h3>

<p>NPP has a great tool for <a href="http://data.nationalpriorities.org/">mapping federal data</a>.  Unfortunately, the <a href="http://data.nationalpriorities.org/mashups/y83ggswab551vaqa/">map for the data is generated in Flash</a>.</p>

<p><em>Flash Map</em></p>

<p><img src="/images/posts/flash-map.jpg" title="&lsquo;Flash Map&rsquo; &lsquo;Flash Map&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Part of our goal for 2013 is to make the main <a href="http://nationalpriorities.org">NPP site</a> more accessible and responsive to varying devices.  I&rsquo;ve been tackling bits and pieces of that goal over the past few months, and figured this event would be a great time to start getting away from flash.  With the help of <a href="http://www.gismatters.com/">Chris Duncan</a> I made some good progress toward that goal (See: JavaScript/D3 Map).</p>

<p><em>JavaScript/D3 State Map</em></p>

<p><img src="/images/posts/d3-map-states.jpg" title="&lsquo;D3 States Map&rsquo; &lsquo;D3 States Map&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>We allow folks to drill into a state to view data at the County level.  However, we feel that painting a picture of budget data showing all counties in the US at once may tell a more compelling story.  I have much more work to do here, however I did make some progress on that front (See: JavaScript/D3 County Map)</p>

<p><em>JavaScript/D3 County Map</em></p>

<p><img src="/images/posts/d3-map-counties.jpg" title="&lsquo;D3 Counties Map&rsquo; &lsquo;D3 Counties Map&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>In general, I&rsquo;m happy with what Chris and I were able to accomplish in a few days.  I had never worked with <a href="http://d3js.org">D3</a> before, which was a fun experience.</p>

<h2>An Awesome Event</h2>

<p>The event organizers deserve a big pat on the back.  The food was great (SUSHI!!!) and there were plenty of healthy choices for sustained energy.  <a href="http://www.umass.edu/">The location</a> couldn&rsquo;t have been more comfortable, and the energy throughout the weekend was really &hellip; energizing.  This was the first time I&rsquo;d attended a civic hacking event (I attended a Facebook event a few years ago) and I&rsquo;d definitely attend again.  I&rsquo;ll be eagerly anticipating this event next year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
